In this video, I will introduce the functions of the virtual model for you.
In the 2025 version, we can use the slide to easily adjust the shape of the male and female virtual models.
To demonstrate this function, we add a female virtual model of FV2.1 and open the virtual model editor.
In the shape of the virtual model size, you will see a new hip part, which includes two adjustable parameters, waistline and size.
In the default situation, both are set to 50%.
You can create various hip shapes by changing these values.
The way the slide is operated is the same as the operation of adjusting the chest shape.
It can be easily controlled by dragging the slide.
You can also make more accurate adjustments by inputting values directly on the right side.
If you want to reset all the changes to default, you can press the reset button in the upper right corner.
Turn the view to the back to observe.
Now let's see how the hip shape changes when adjusting each parameter.
The first parameter is the waistline.
The waistline can adjust the natural waistline between the hip and thigh sides.
Slide the slide to the left to reduce the waistline value.
Note that when moving the slide for the first time, it may pop up a message window.
If you choose not to display, the next time you move the slide, the window will not appear.
Press OK to confirm, then move the slide to the left.
As the value decreases, you will see that the curve on both sides of the hip is more curved.
Slide the slide to the right to move the slide, which can fill the volume on both sides of the hip, and thus form a rounder hip shape.
Next, let's create a more flat or more curved hip by adjusting the second parameter size.
Let's turn to the side view to observe.
You will see that there are two options at the bottom of the slide.
If you slide a slide, you can create a more flat hip shape.
Slide a slide can increase the size of the upper part of the hip and improve the appearance of the hip.
This function is also used in male virtual models.
First, let's add a male virtual model in the mv2.1 version.
You will find the hip in the same position.
The type and O-line and volume parameters are the same as female virtual models due to the same operation process.
You can directly adjust the value and adjust the hip according to your needs.
Please note that adjusting these hip parameters will not affect the size, value, or measurement of the hip or lower hip.
By using the new function in the virtual model editor, you can easily create various hip shapes.
In the previous version, we have to use the third-party software to name each pair of shoes or earrings correctly,
in order to correctly define the shoes in the colo.
In the latest version, the customized symmetry configuration will become more convenient.
Next, we will use shoes as an example.
First, open a virtual model.
Then, click on the virtual model in the main menu bar.
Select the customized configuration.
In the customized configuration, find the configuration type and select shoes.
Then you can choose flat shoes or high heels.
Here, use high heels to demonstrate.
Next, click on the file plus icon.
Insert the file containing two shoes at the same time.
After this update, we also support the file with the input OBJ format.
After the update, colo can automatically identify each shoe.
There is no need to name it by left or right.
In addition, in the new version, you can directly select two shoes.
Right-click and select shoes.
You can see that the shoes will be displayed in red.
It's just the shoes you chose.
If you set it wrong, you can right-click again and select cancel settings as shoes.
This step is only applicable to high heels.
Because it needs to automatically raise the virtual model's heel to adapt the heel when loading.
Next, we will save the shoes.
So, next time, you can directly use the saved configuration file.
I hope these functions can help you optimize the workflow.
Make the process of customizing the matching configuration more convenient.
Next, I will introduce you to the 2025.0 version.
Another workflow that can greatly simplify the workflow.
Now you can see that the virtual model currently has a side position.
In the previous version, if you want to do the mirror effect of the current position, you must modify the position from the beginning.
But in the new version, you only need to right-click on the virtual model and then select the flip position option.
This will immediately convert the virtual model into a flip position.
And the costume will also be simulated accordingly.
This function allows you to try various positions and easily flip them.
Therefore, it is more free to test the effect of different angles when simulated.
In the new version, the virtual model editor also has another important update.
You can create and edit.
The chest of the female virtual model is the same size as the cup.
Let's see how to edit it.
Open the virtual model editor.
Under the virtual model size option card.
In the width, select the chest.
Now you can set the detailed information.
Activate the cup size option.
After activating, you can set the standard size of the chest.
You can change the number of sizes.
The smallest value is 3.
The largest value is 6.
In addition, you can also change the name and value of each cup size.
This value indicates the difference between the chest and the lower chest.
If you want to reset it to default, you can click reset.
After setting up.
You can exit the detailed information window.
Now you can choose the cup size according to the previous size preset.
Just click the down arrow.
Select the cup size you want to use.
The chest cup size will be adjusted accordingly.
You can see the value just set is displayed at the bottom of the chest size.
This function can help you create a more standard chest size.
Make the virtual model chest adjustment process more standardized.
Use the
reset.
first.
2.
to make a virtual model chest adjustment as usual.